<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://apps.nextcloud.com/schema/apps/info.xsd">
    <id>mkvplayer</id>
    <name>MKV Player</name>
    <summary>Play Matroska (.mkv) video in the Viewer — in-browser, offline, no server transcoding.</summary>
    <description><![CDATA[
Plays Matroska `.mkv` files right inside Nextcloud's built-in Viewer. Click a file and it plays
in place — no download, no server-side conversion, no external services.

**How it works**

Everything runs in the viewer's browser. The file is remuxed on the fly from Matroska to
fragmented MP4 and played through Media Source Extensions (WebAssembly). Your server just serves
the original file over HTTP range requests — it does no transcoding and stores nothing extra.

**Subtitles**

Text (SRT/WebVTT), ASS/SSA (rendered with libass, with embedded fonts and styling) and PGS image
subtitles. Multiple tracks are supported, including two shown at once.

**Codec support — please read**

Because the **video is remuxed, not transcoded**, the video track must be one your browser can
already decode:

- **H.264 / AVC** — plays virtually everywhere.
- **HEVC / H.265, VP9, AV1** — only where the browser and OS support them (varies by device; HEVC
  in particular is limited outside Safari and hardware-accelerated Edge/Chrome).

Video in a codec your browser cannot decode will not play — the app does not convert video.

**Audio** is more flexible. Browser-native tracks play directly, and several non-native codecs
(**Vorbis, AC-3, E-AC-3, DTS core**) are transcoded in the browser to AAC-LC or Opus using a
royalty-free ffmpeg.wasm core that ships with the app and is served from your own server (fully
offline). **Not supported out of the box:** TrueHD/MLP, DTS-HD and HE-AAC — excluded for
patent/licensing reasons. An administrator can point the app at a self-built, fuller ffmpeg.wasm
build to add them (note: that makes each viewer's browser contact the configured host).

**Free & paid (freemium)**

The app is free and fully functional. Unlicensed instances show a small watermark in the corner of
the video; an optional paid license removes it. **License validation is done entirely offline on
your own server** — the key is never sent to us or any third party, and no usage data is
transmitted.

**Privacy**

By default the app makes no external network requests: playback, audio transcoding and license
validation all happen locally. The only exception is the optional, admin-enabled external
ffmpeg.wasm source described above.

**Note:** `.mka` (Matroska audio) is not enabled by default — Nextcloud has no built-in MIME
mapping for it. The handler already registers `audio/x-matroska`, so an administrator can enable
`.mka` by adding that MIME mapping — but this is a video player, so audio-only playback is just a
byproduct.
    ]]></description>
    <version>0.1.0</version>
    <licence>agpl</licence>
    <author>David Schneider</author>
    <namespace>MkvPlayer</namespace>
    <category>multimedia</category>
    <bugs>https://github.com/davidschneider/play-mkv.js/issues</bugs>
    <dependencies>
        <nextcloud min-version="28" max-version="34"/>
    </dependencies>
    <settings>
        <admin>OCA\MkvPlayer\Settings\LicenseAdminSettings</admin>
        <admin-section>OCA\MkvPlayer\Settings\AdminSection</admin-section>
    </settings>
</info>
